Anway Pimpalkar

apimpal1@jhu.edu | anway.me | +1 (443) 687 8833 | in () (/anwaypimpalkar) | US National

Summary

Research and development oriented individual with background in electronics, signal processing, and artificial intelligence. Rounded prior experience through multiple positions at universities and startups. Excellent creativity, leadership, and teamwork skills demonstrated through projects and extra-curricular activities.

Education

Johns Hopkins University - Baltimore, USA

Starting August 2023

MSE in Biomedical Engineering

College of Engineering Pune (now COEP Technological University) – Pune, India

Aug 2019 to May 2023

BTech in Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering | CGPA: 8.24 / 10.00 (First Class with Distinction)

Publications

- [2] Pimpalkar A*., Niture D. Building Contactless Elevators with tinyML using Person Detection and Keyword Spotting. Under review for IEEE Micro: Special Issue on tinyML. 2023.
- [1] Pimpalkar A*., Patole R., Kamble K., Shindikar M. Performance Evaluation of Vanilla, Residual, and Dense 2D U-Net Architectures for Skull Stripping of Augmented 3D T1-weighted MRI Head Scans. Under review for Springer's Communications in Computer and Information Science Series. 2023. [arXiv:2211.16570]

Notable Awards and Fellowships

Best Paper | 2nd International Conference on Biomedical Engineering Science and Technology

Certificate | Feb 2023

• Awarded for the publication [1] listed in the above section.

Mitacs Globalink Graduate Fellowship | Mitacs

Dec 2022

• Fellowship of CA\$ 15,000 towards pursuing a graduate program at a Canadian university - did not avail.

Best Project | 5th IEEE National Level Project Competition

Certificate | Jun 2021

Out of a pool of 1000+ projects for 'Smart Elevator Systems using Embedded Machine Learning.'

Research Experience

Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Bombay – Research Intern

Dec 2022 to Present

Mumbai, India (Hybrid) | Supervisor: Prof. Nivethida Thirugnanasambandam

Domains: Motor Neurophysiology and Cognition, Neural Signal Processing, Feature Engineering, Machine Learning

- Elucidating the electrophysiological correlates of the prospective component of sense of agency and intentional binding using machine learning.
- Identifying premotor EEG features that can predict the quantitative intentional binding for a particular action in cohorts of healthy individuals.

COEP Technological University – Undergraduate Researcher

Aug 2022 to Present

Pune, India (On-site) | Supervisors: Prof. Rashmika Patole, Prof. Ketaki Kamble, Prof. Mahesh Shindikar Domains: Neuroimaging, Deep Learning, Neuropsychology

- Identifying the regional brain volume changes or neuroimaging biomarkers that can be seen in the sMRIs of patients diagnosed with Major Depressive Disorder using deep learning, and trying to predict feasibility of early risk evaluation.
- Developed skull stripping pipelines robust to the multi-scanner variability issues using U-Net neural network architectures and achieved a preliminary accuracy of 99.75% on test data.

Dalhousie University – Mitacs Globalink Research Intern

Certificate | May 2022 to Aug 2022

Nova Scotia, Canada (On-site) | Supervisor: Prof. Travis Esau

Domains: Precision Agriculture, Point Cloud Processing, Image Processing and Segmentation, Electronic Control Systems

- Awarded and funded through Mitacs Globalink, a highly competitive program for undergraduates worldwide.
- Implemented real-time point cloud segmentation and volumetric analysis of the wild blueberries harvested in bins within a ±10% accuracy range using industrial Time-of-Flight and RGB imaging tools.
- Designed a control system to automate the harvester head height using prescription maps of wild blueberry fields collected using multi-spectral drone data.

Research Experience (continued)

Queliz Lifetech - Research Intern

Certificate | Jun 2021 to Sept 2021

Pune, India (Remote) | Supervisor: Mr. Swapnil Bukshete

Domains: Rehabilitation Science, Control Systems, Digital Electronics, Computer Vision

- Developed novel control system prototypes for a hand rehabilitation device to help patients with acute burn injuries to their MCP, DIP, and PIP joints.
- Generated computerized models of finger movement paths in flexion-extension cycles and a GUI-based feedback system to calibrate and control a lead-screw actuation mechanism based on STM32.

Academic Projects

PicoBoo - Thermal Imagery based Security System using Deep Learning

GitHub | Jan 2022 to May 2022

College of Engineering Pune – India | Supervisor: Prof. Srinivas Mahajan

Domains: Computer Vision, Microcontroller Programming, Web Development, Internet of Things

• Evaluated the performance of multiple CNNs trained on a constructed thermal image dataset; optimized them for accuracy metrics and latency at the edge, and enabled remote access to the inferences through a PaaS model.

TinyMLevator - Smart Elevator System using Embedded Machine Learning

GitHub | Apr 2021 to May 2021

College of Engineering Pune – Pune, India | Supervisor: Prof. Deeplaxmi Niture

Domains: Deep Learning, Microcontrollers, TinyML, Signal Processing

- Constructed a novel multi-tenant TinyML based device capable of detecting a person standing in front of an elevator and identifying a number spoken, indicating the floor number the user would like to reach.
- Best Project Award at the 5th IEEE National Level Project Competition (Mysore, India 2021).

CovPrev - COVID-19 Symptom Checking and Sanitization Unit with App

GitHub | Feb 2021 to Mar 2021

College of Engineering Pune – Pune, India | Supervisor: Prof. Neelima Kolhare

Domains: Microcontrollers, Internet of Things, Web Development

• Designed a pandemic-relevant system using physiological sensors and assemblies to provide selective entry to venues based on a patient's health conditions with a mobile application to access to real-time graphical visualizations.

Conference Activity

2 nd International Conference on Biomedical Engineering Science and Technology NIT Raipur, India Oral Presentation Best Paper Award	Feb 2023
3 rd No Garland Neuroscience (NGN) Conference IISER Pune, India Oral and Poster Presentation	Feb 2023
Canadian Society for Bioengineering 2022 AGM Conference Charlottetown, Prince Edward Island, Canada Volunteer	July 2022
Self-Learning Initiatives	All Records
Introduction to Neurohacking in R Johns Hopkins University on Coursera	Sept 2022
Fundamental Neuroscience for Neuroimaging Johns Hopkins University on Coursera	Sept 2022

Using Python for Research | HarvardX on edX Extra-Curricular Activities and Leadership Roles

Tiny Machine Learning (TinyML) Specialization | HarvardX on edX

Deep Learning Specialization | Deep Learning. AI on Coursera

COEP Rowing Team | 1X and 2X Sculler

Jan 2020 to May 2023

Mar 2022

Apr 2021

Mar 2021

• Won multiple race events and awards commending enthusiasm and skill. Represented Pune City at inter-zonal races.

COEP's Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Club | Research Lead & Member

Sept 2020 to May 2023

• Led the research activities of the club consisting of 49 members, focused on tracking vehicle plates on campus.

COEP Impressions (Annual Cultural Festival) | Head of Events and Proshows

Aug 2019 to Jun 2022

• Led 15 members responsible for planning and executing concerts, competitions, and celebrity management.

YOUmanity Pune | Founding Member

Oct 2015 to Oct 2018

Led 150 volunteers of the non-profit organization aiming to spread humanity in Pune, India.